Guide to the Tamiment Playhouse Records TAM.107
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Playhouse Records
1927-1987
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Playhouse
Tamiment Institute
Kolatch, Myron
TAM.107
16.25 Linear Feet (34 boxes)
1 8mm_Film_Reel
The Tamiment Playhouse was a summer theater at Camp Tamiment, which operated from 1921-1965 as an educational and recreational summer resort for socialists near Bushkill, Pennsylvania. TPH became a workshop for theater, dance, film, and television and entertainment figures such as actors Danny Kaye, Bea Arthur, Imogene Coca, and Carol Burnett; directors Max Liebman, Herb Ross, and Joe Layton; choreographer Jerome Robbins; and writers Woody Allen and Neil Simon performed and staged their work there. The collection includes scores, scripts, clippings, correspondence, ephemera, The Tamiment Story film, and casefiles for interviews with TPH alumni.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Tamiment Institute, 1983. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1983.002 and 1983.006. Additional materials in this collection were found in the repository in 2014. The accession number associated with these materials is 2014.085.
After the Tamiment Playhouse records were donated to NYU in 1983, the archive collected additional photographs, playbills, music scores and other memorabilia to augment the collection. A number of small donations were made at this time.
In January 2026, The Tamiment Story film was found in the repository and incorporated into the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical Note
The Tamiment Playhouse was a resident summer theater that operated between 1921 and 1960 at Camp Tamiment, an adult summer camp in Pennsylvania's Pocono Mountains. Camp Tamiment was an educational and recreational summer resort for socialists and their families near Bushkill, Pennsylvania, from 1921 until its sale in 1965 to commercial interests. TPH became a creative outlet for theater, dance, film, and television practitioners of the mid-twentieth century. Actors such as Danny Kaye, Bea Arthur, Imogene Coca, and Carol Burnett, directors Max Liebman, Herb Ross, and Joe Layton, choreographer Jerome Robbins, and writers Woody Allen and Neil Simon are some of the entertainment figures who stayed at Camp Tamiment. Much of the original material performed at Tamiment found its way to the professional stage, Broadway, and television, and much of it reflects the predominantly Jewish cultural and politically liberal orientation of the camp and its residents.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Playhouse Records (1927-1987) contain records related to the history of Camp Tamiment and the creative works produced there. The history of the camp is portrayed in publications, ephemera, correspondence, The Tamiment Story film, interview transcripts, and scrapbooks. Creative works in the collection include playbills for productions, sketches and lyrics, and musical scores.
Arrangement
Organized into five series, with Series I organized into two subseries:
Series I. History
Series I.A. Playbills
Series I.B. Camp Tamiment: Documents, Publications, and Ephemera
Series II. Alumni and Associates
Series III. Sketches and Lyrics
Series IV. Music
Series V. Scrapbooks.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
OH 031: Tamiment Playhouse Alumni Oral Histories Collection, including 62 interviews (1980-1988) and 28 audiotapes of shows (1955-1960).
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact NYU Special Collections (special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596) with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Theater -- Pennsylvania -- History -- 20th century.; Dramatists -- United States.; Jewish entertainers -- United States.; Musical theater -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Jewish composers -- United States; Scripts (documents); Jewish musicians -- United States.; Pocono Mountains (Pa.).; Transcripts.; Scrapbooks.; Clippings (information artifacts); Printed ephemera.; Magazines (Periodicals); Correspondence.; Scores.; Summer theater -- Pennsylvania -- Pocono Mountains -- History; Theater -- Political aspects -- Pennsylvania -- Pocono Mountains.; Theater -- Pennsylvania -- Bushkill Falls (Pa.); Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr. (Arthur Meier), 1917-2007; Camp Tamiment (Pa.); Tamiment Institute; Kugler, Israel, 1917-2007; Shawn, Dick; Allen, Woody, 1935-; Channing, Carol; Liebman, Max; Goren, Lewis M.; Pogany, Willy, 1882-1955.; Barer, Marshall; LoMonaco, Martha Schmoyer; Corey, Irwin; Robbins, Jerome.; Simon, Neil; Bock, Jerry; Tamiment Institute; Kolatch, Myron
- Series I: History
  - Subseries I:A: Playbills
    Arrangement
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Playbill, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Playbill, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1A)
    - Playbills, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Playbills, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Playbills, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Playbills, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Playbills, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Playbills, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Playbills, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Playbills, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Playbills, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Playbills, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10A)
    - Playbills, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Playbills, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Playbills, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Playbills, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Playbills, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Playbills, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Playbills, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Playbills, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Playbills, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Playbills, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Playbills, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Playbills, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Subseries I:B: Camp Tamiment: Documents, Publications, and Ephemera
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - Actors Equity Association: Tamiment Institute, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Admiral Broadway Revue(television), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Afternoon of a Faun (background), Nijinsky, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Annual reports, 1934-1944 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Architecture (Architectural Forum), 1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Architecture (Architectural Forum), 1948 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Art exhibitions, 1940-1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Book Award, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Caesar, Sid: Where Have I Been? excerpts, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Camp Tamiment promotional movie script, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Carlines (Camp Carlisle daily paper), 1927 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cast lists, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Catch a Star (Broadway Show), 1955 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Chamber music, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Constellation room, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Dancing in Summer Camps by Jerome Andrews, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Fat Tuesday review, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Forest Park history, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Golf course, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Histories, early, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - "History," anonymous typescript, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - IRS Rulings, AGVA performers, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Kober, Arthur: Counselor of Camp 'Kare-free', undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Lecture Series, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Lecture Series, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Lecture/Concert Series, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Lecture/Concert Series, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Lecture/Concert Series, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Lecture/Concert Series, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Lecture/Concert Series, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Lecture/Concert Series, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Lecture/Concerts/Special Events, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Levitas, Willard: Employment Contract, 1947; 2014.085 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Levitas, Willard: scrapbook 1, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Levitas, Willard: scrapbook 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 11A)
      - Levitas, Willard: painting, June 8, 1950 (Flat-file-folder 3, Tray 3)
    - Make Mine Manhattan by Max Liebman, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - New Faces of 1943 by Leonard Sillman, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Once upon a Mattress, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Photographs (Unidentified), undated (Box 3, Folder 14A)
    - Planning a Convention at Tamiment brochure, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Playhouse history: articles (published), undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Playhouse lights: plots/blueprints, 1950's (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Poconos history, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Pocono Mountains ad brochure: NY Times, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Postcards, 1950-1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Program of Traditional Jewish Music: photo, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Rand School: 45th Anniversary booklet, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Rand School history, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Straw Hat Revue: music, lyric, sketch, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Straw Hat Revue: playbill, reviews, PR, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Swire, Willard: Actor's Equity, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Tamiment Playhouse '49 (Cartoon), 1949 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS002, Folder 1)
    - The Tamiment Story, undated; cuid45197 (Box Shared Tamiment 170, 8mm film reel cuid45197)
      Scope and Contents
      This film was likely edited by Lucille Kallen and Mel Tolkin, and produced by Willard Levitas. The film is in poor condition, making credits difficult to decipher.
    - Tamiment Times, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Tamiment Times, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Tamiment Times, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Tami-Mentor(daily paper), 1935 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Tami-Mentor, 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Tami-Mentor, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Tamiment's New Theater: articles (published), 1941 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - The Tavern Log (Camp Log Tavern), 1931 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - The Tavern Log (Camp Log Tavern), 1932 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - 10th Anniversary Camper Census, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Tocks Island Dam Project, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Ye Upstagers Guild Flyer, undated; 2014.085 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Your Show of Shows: playbill & Life magazine, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Camp Tamiment Architectural Drawing, March, 1943 (Box Shared Tamiment 020, Folder 1)
- Series II: Alumni & Associates
  Series II. Alumni & Associates, consists of Martha LoMonaco's correspondence, notes, clippings and some transcripts relating to her sixty-two interviews (1950s focus) with Playhouse alumni and associates. Within this series, the term "alumni" refers to theatre workers, and the term "associates" refers to supporters and camp staff.
  Arranged alphabetically by interviewee's last name.
  - Allen, Woody: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 1, Box 37)
  - Alvarez, Anita: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Andrews, Jerome: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bales, William: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Barer, Marshall: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Basy, Sid: associate, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Berkowitz, Sol: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bird, Dorothy: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Blaker, Alex and Martha: associates, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Blaker, Ben: associate, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Bock, Jerry: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Bohnert, Bill: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Boris, Ruthanna: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Bostick, Jack: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Bozeman, Beverly: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Brenner, Yvonne: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Brown, Forman: associate, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Bruskin, Perry: associate; Green Mansions, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Burnett, Carol: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Carroll, Pat: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Channing, Carol: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Coca, Imogene: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Cook, Barbara: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Connell, Gordon: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous: associates, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Corey, Irwin: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Daniels, Danny: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Deems, Mickey: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Dishy, Bob: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Ellstein (Hoffman), Sylvia: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Fine, Sylvia, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Frankel, Beulah: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Gale, Gerri: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Ganz, Blanche Felder: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Garrett, Betty: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Gladstone, Saul: associate (re: White Roe), undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Goldfarb, Philip: associate (re: Danny Kaye; Tummling; White Roe), undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Goren, Lew "Snappy:" associate, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Grant, Lee: alumni, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Greenberg, Jules: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Greenberg, Nat: associate, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Greene, Milton: associate, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Hack, Moe and Paula (Cohen): alumni, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Hall, George: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Halliday, Buzz: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Hamilton Trio: alumni, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Hartman, Don: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Hayes, Dorsha: alumna, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Hayes, Dorsha: 1920's dance bills, pageants, etc, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Hollister, David: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Holt, Calvin: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Izen, Marshall: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Johnson, Arte E.: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Kert, Larry: alumnus, undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Kugler, Israel: associate, undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Levitas, Mike: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Layton, Joe: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Liebman, Max: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Liebman, Max; correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Liff, Samuel "Biff": alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Loudon, Dorothy: alumna, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - MacDonald, Marie: associate, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Magaziner, Elliot: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Magaziner, Elliot: alumnus (donation of 1942 bills and photos) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Mailly, Bertha: associate, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Maltby, Richard Jr.: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Marks, Sylvia and Marco Roasales: alumni, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Mata & Hari: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Meyer, Don: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Meyer, John: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Peerce, Larry: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Perlowin, Gene: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Pockriss, Lee: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Pogany, Willy: associate, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Questel, Mae: associate, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Remo, Ken: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Robbins, Jerome: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Rodgers, Mary: alumna, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Rogers, David: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Ross, Herbert: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Scheiner, Harry: associate (re: Max Liebman), undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur Jr.: associate, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Seltzer, Ellen (Blaker): associate, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Shapiro, Gertrude: associate (?), undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Shapiro, Herman, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Shawn, Dick: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Sherman, Vincent: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Simon, Cyril: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Simon, Danny: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 34, Box 37)
  - Simon, Neil "Doc:" alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 35, Box 37)
  - Simone, Arlene: alumna, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Solov, Zachary: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Starbuck, James: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Strouse, Charles: correspondence, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Tamiment "Alumni" correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Thompson, Jay: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Tishler, Anne: associate, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Theodore, Lee (Becker): alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Tobias, George: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Tolkin, Mel: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Valbor, Kirsten: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Vestoff, Virginia: alumna, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Wainer, Lee: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Wallach, Ira: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Warren, Frank L., M.D.: associate, undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Waterman, Texie: alumna, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Weiner, John / White Roe Resort: associate, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Weisfeld, Zelma: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - West, Bernie: alumnus, undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Wright, Robert / Forrest, Chet: alumni, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Series III: Sketches & Lyrics
  Arranged alphabetically by the creator's last name.
  - Allen, Woody: material copies, 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Barer, Marshall & Dean Fuller: sketch/lyrics, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Ebb, Fred & Paul Klein: lyric, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Barer, Marshall & Mary Rodgers: lyric, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Boland, Clay Jr.: sketch/lyric, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Canter, Walt: sketch, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Der Richtiga Mikado, original & Gildemeister translations: sketch, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Fat Tuesday (jazz opera), 1957 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Flender, Harold: sketch, undated; 2014.085 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Green, Phil: sketch, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Grudeff, Marian & Ray Jessel: sketch, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Jessel, Ray: lyric, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Johnson, James: lyric, undated; 2014.085 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Kallen, Lucille: sketch, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Liebman, Mac [Max]: Vot is Kemp Life (book), undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Liebman, Max: "A Broadway Revue Every Week", undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Liebman, Max: "Make Mine Borscht", undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Liebman, Max: "Once is Enough" (article), undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Liebman, Max: Lyric Notebook 1, A-D, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Liebman, Max: Lyric Notebook 1, E-H, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Liebman, Max: Lyric Notebook 2, I-L, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Liebman, Max: Lyric Notebook 2, L-O, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Liebman, Max: "Sadie the Bookkeeper" (sketch), undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Liebman, Max: Sketch Notebook 1, A-B, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Liebman, Max: Sketch Notebook 1, B-C, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Liebman, Max: Sketch Notebook 2, D-F, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Liebman, Max: Sketch Notebook 2, F-G, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Liebman, Max: Sketch Notebook 3, M, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Liebman, Max: Sketch Notebook 3, M-O, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Liebman, Max: Sketch Notebook 4, P, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Liebman, Max: Sketch Notebook 4, P-R, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Liebman, Max: Sketch Notebook 5, S-T, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Liebman, Max: Sketch Notebook 5, T-X, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Marks, Dennis & Alan Freidman: sketch/lyric, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Meyer, Don & Sol Berkowitz: lyric, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Meyer, Don & Lee Pockriss: Panic on Seventh Ave.: sketch/lyric, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Meyer, John: sketch, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Meyer, John & Clay Boland, Jr.: sketch/lyric, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Meyer, John & Ray Jessell: lyric, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous: sketch/lyric, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Panich, David: sketches, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Rosner, Paul & Claibe Richardson: lyrics sketch/ lyric, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Simon, Neil & Danny: sketches, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - That Great Big Candy Store up in the Sky, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Thompson, Jay: sketch/lyrics, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Tolkin, Mel: sketches, undated; 2014.085 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Vinavar, Steven & Sol Berkowitz: lyric, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Welch, Ken: sketches, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Welch, Ken & Sol Berkowitz: sketch/lyric, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Series IV: Music
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  Series IV. Music Scores consists of handwritten and annotated but often unsigned music scores, 1952-1960, most for individual songs, some for shows. A notable score is The Princess & the Pea, which later became the Broadway musical Once upon a Mattress.
  - Aim High, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - All the News, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - America Be Seated, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - America Be Seated, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Apes: song & ballet, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Art Theatre, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Back in the Trunk, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bacon & Eggs, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Baker's Sketch& Syncopated Clock (incidental music), undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bells ballet: Tunick, J., 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Billy's Comin' Home, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - The Boy Upstairs, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Britannia (incidental music), 1960 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Case of the Hum-Drum Killer, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Charley, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Churinga, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Circus Sort of Day, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - The City's Just a Jungle, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Cloud 14, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Comedy of Art, 1957-1959 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Conformity, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Dance Hall Dinah, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Deep are the Roots, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - De Revolution is Late, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Doctors' Lament, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Don't Tell a Soul (finale), 1958 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Dottie's Single (Dorothy Aull), 1960 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Durante, Jimmy Music (incidental), undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Dusty Road, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Egyptianella, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Eileen, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Elementary Geometry, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Elephant Blues, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Everything, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Facts and Figures, 1954, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Feather in My Cap, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Fetes and Phantoms, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - The First Fall Day, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - For the Birds, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Fra Diavolo, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Frank Drac Wolf, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - From the Top, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Good Girl, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Gotta Get into the Act, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Gotta Make Time, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Grandma Noses, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Grow a Beard, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Guiness Bit, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Happy Endings, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Happy Endsville, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Lost from Happy Medium, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Happy Pill Dance, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Hard to Get, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Hey Chicago: Finale, 1955, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Hire a Guy You Can Blame, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Hold Me Hamlet, 1956-1957 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Hold Me Hamlet opening, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Boy in Black" from Hold Me Hamlet, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 5)